<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Hi! I&#x27;m Ashley Miller, user experience designer</title>
    <link href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com" />
    <updated>2021-05-03T20:53:23-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ashley Miller</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.ashleymmiller.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Find my device turned fleet management</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Miller</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/find-my-device-turned-fleet-management/"/>
        <id>https://www.ashleymmiller.com/find-my-device-turned-fleet-management/</id>

        <updated>2021-05-03T19:30:27-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/p1eicnfe4vbh1nikt1t1n7h1fiv3.png" alt="An android device with a screen displaying multiple devices and statuses" />
                     Project In an effort to modernize day-to-day activities in the stores,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/p1eicnfe4vbh1nikt1t1n7h1fiv3.png" alt="An android device with a screen displaying multiple devices and statuses" />
                <div class="project-description">
<h2>Project</h2>
<p>In an effort to modernize day-to-day activities in the stores, business gave them handheld and tablet devices. Handhelds had been going missing at an alarming rate. They looked like phones, which meant they were very attractive for thieves and had a small form factor, so were easily misplaced by well-meaning employees. Over the two years that the modernization project had been active, the company had lost several hundred thousand dollars worth of devices.</p>
<ul>
<li>My role: Lead UX designer</li>
<li>Team: Product owner, architect, lead developer, researcher, ui designer</li>
</ul>
<h2>Objective</h2>
<h3>Business objective</h3>
<ul>
<li>Decrease the number of missing devices and save the company money by creating a find my device tool</li>
</ul>
<h3>UX objective</h3>
<ul>
<li>Find a way to preemptively avoid device loss</li>
<li>Create a find my device tool</li>
</ul>
<h2>Work</h2>
<p>During previous research outings to the stores, we had heard many comments from the stores about their devices. In general, they didn't really see what was so special about the devices. The lack of training left stores unable to understand exactly everything that the devices were capable of; they saw the devices as smaller telxon (scanner) guns. They treated them the same as well. No one ever wanted to steal the old telxon guns, so store employees would leave the handheld devices out on carts or shelves during their tasks.</p>
<p>Compounding all these problems was a lack of accountability. These devices were communal and did not require a login to access. Store employees did not feel responsible for these devices and there was no way to make them responsible for the devices.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--wide" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/p1eic3mu2esc6brf1hh71qf81r667.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2esc6brf1hh71qf81r667-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2esc6brf1hh71qf81r667-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2esc6brf1hh71qf81r667-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2esc6brf1hh71qf81r667-lg.jpg 1024w"  alt="Our original storyboard for the find my device function" width="1000" height="166">
<figcaption >Our original storyboard for the find my device function</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>We introduced our architect, dev team, and UI designer to the project early on so that we could brainstorm and provide feedback on all of those concepts. Before we got attached to any one idea, we wanted to confirm that it was possible using the infrastructure and devices available to us.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/p1eic3mu2cb8f1u141pat1rb7ckn3.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2cb8f1u141pat1rb7ckn3-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2cb8f1u141pat1rb7ckn3-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2cb8f1u141pat1rb7ckn3-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2cb8f1u141pat1rb7ckn3-lg.jpg 1024w"  alt="Brainstormed list of features by release" width="1000" height="268">
<figcaption >Brainstormed list of features by release</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Ultimately, we recommended the project in phases:</p>
<ul>
<li>Phase 0: Paper sign-out sheet</li>
<li>Phase 1: Find My Device MVP release</li>
<li>Phase 2: Devices full release</li>
</ul>
<h3>Phase 0: Paper sign-out sheet</h3>
<p>Many stores had already created their own version of the sign out sheet. We provided a version that would standardize the process across the chain.</p>
<h3>Phase 1: Find My Device MVP release</h3>
<p>This was the meat of what our business partners wanted. The app listed the devices in a single store and allowed a team member to tap a button that would make a specific device ring. The device would ring for five minutes or until the ringtone was deactivated from the now-found device.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/p1eic3mu2e1e16hbq4v817fe1vl78.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2e1e16hbq4v817fe1vl78-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2e1e16hbq4v817fe1vl78-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2e1e16hbq4v817fe1vl78-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2e1e16hbq4v817fe1vl78-lg.jpg 1024w"  alt="Phase 1 sketches" width="1000" height="547">
<figcaption >Phase 1 sketches</figcaption>
</figure>
<h3>Phase 2: Devices full release</h3>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-columns="3">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/gallery/p1eic3mu2cb3c1io627m177o144e4.jpg" data-size="804x1000"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/gallery/p1eic3mu2cb3c1io627m177o144e4-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="955"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/gallery/p1eic3mu2daul1ig11d0l137611j5.jpg" data-size="1000x625"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/gallery/p1eic3mu2daul1ig11d0l137611j5-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="480"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/gallery/p1eic3mu2d1vod1ua51r88s779956.jpg" data-size="1000x559"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/gallery/p1eic3mu2d1vod1ua51r88s779956-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="429"></a></figure>
</div></div>
<p>To try and promote ownership of and responsibility for the devices, we wanted the team members to have a set of tools that would allow them to manage their devices. At a glance, they could see all of their devices in the store, just like in the MVP, but the full release added:</p>
<ul>
<li>Who logged into and out of the device and when</li>
<li>The battery level of the device</li>
<li>The storage capacity of the device</li>
<li>What Wi-Fi access point it was attached to</li>
<li>The ability to nickname devices</li>
</ul>
<p>The first four features were utility based: They allowed team members to better manage the devices they had and also provided a paper trail. If your name was attached to the device and that device went missing, you would be the one in trouble for it. The final feature, adding a nickname to devices, also promoted ownership: It's much harder to get rid of something you've named.</p>
<p>We brought out a <a href="https://9lnd3u.axshare.com/start_here.html" title="Link: Prototype">prototype</a> to the stores to get feedback. Certain features were tightened up, others added to the backlog. Overall, the store employees seemed happy with the new tool.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/p1eic3mu2f1pk28gmj8m19941u7d9.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2f1pk28gmj8m19941u7d9-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2f1pk28gmj8m19941u7d9-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2f1pk28gmj8m19941u7d9-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/3/responsive/p1eic3mu2f1pk28gmj8m19941u7d9-lg.jpg 1024w"  alt="" width="981" height="494">
<figcaption >The anticipated timeline of releases</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>End result</h2>
<p>After 4 months:</p>
<ul>
<li>Used to find over 21,000 devices</li>
<li>Helped to avoid over $1,000,000 in replacement costs</li>
<li>Favorite nicknames include: “El Diablo,” “The Hammer,” and “Don’t Lose Me”</li>
</ul>
<h2>Reflection</h2>
<p>It was a lot of work to get the project to a state to present to business, but when we did, they were floored. We were able to address the problem and explain why we thought that our proposed design would be an even better solution. We had a story to tell and research to back up the story, as well as a timeline of when we could expect said story to be completed. After the success of this project, I used it as a template for all projects going forward.</p>
<p>Of all the projects I've ever done in my career, this project has come closest to my ideal process. We were able to use research to inform our opinions around a business request, create a solution that addressed the request and then some, design a progressively more complex tool through several phases, and confirm our designs through in-store research. If only all projects could be like this.</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>My Resume</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Miller</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/my-resume/"/>
        <id>https://www.ashleymmiller.com/my-resume/</id>

        <updated>2021-05-03T19:18:57-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Experience ISACA · Senior User Experience Designer · November 2020 - Present Walgreens ·&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>Experience</h2>
<p><strong>ISACA</strong> · Senior User Experience Designer · <i>November 2020 - Present</i></p>
<ul>
<li>UX team lead</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Walgreens</strong> · Senior User Experience Designer · <i>May 2017 - November 2020</i></p>
<ul>
<li>Integral part of the Enterprise team, dedicated to improving store employee tools and workflows</li>
<li>Daily collaboration with product owners, business analysts, project managers, UX researchers, a UI designer, a team of 30 developers, and a dozen QA</li>
<li>Designed an order fulfillment product for the upcoming drive-thru and curbside pickup process</li>
<li>Designed a device management product to help Walgreens avoid over $1,000,000 in device replacement costs</li>
<li>Took over designing the new inventory management app for Walgreens stores</li>
<li>Led the design of Boots’ beauty clienteling pilot and improved basket size by 25% and overall conversions by 34%</li>
<li>Designed and managed employee-facing intranet revamp project</li>
<li>Owned process improvements for deploying new applications to in-store tablets and handhelds via meeting management, documentation, and new application design</li>
<li>Recipients of Walgreens’ Champion of Champions 2018: Best User Experience Team for our contributions to modernizing store technology</li>
<li>Created wireframes, mock-ups, prototypes, site maps, user journeys, and information architecture for websites and mobile applications</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Grainger</strong> · User Experience Architect, Zoro.com · <i>March 2016 - May 2017</i></p>
<ul>
<li>
<div>Early member of the Zoro.com user experience team, dedicated to improving the website experience</div>
</li>
<li>
<div>Daily collaboration with a team of 5 developers, project managers, and an SEO manager</div>
</li>
<li>
<div>Expanded the research program to include quantitative tests (A/B tests, card sorts, first-click tests) and remote customer interviews</div>
</li>
<li>
<div>Designed and coded A/B tests to determine which design would increase purchases</div>
</li>
<li>
<div>Redesigned the homepage to increase traffic to category pages</div>
</li>
<li>
<div>Iterated on the shopping cart to assist customers in finding the best deal and related products</div>
</li>
<li>
<div>Collaborated with the Grainger legal team to update a flow for purchasing items that could be harmful to users</div>
</li>
</ul>
<div>
<p><strong>Overture Promotions</strong> · eCommerce Website Manager · <i>October 2014 - March 2016</i></p>
<ul>
<li>Integral member of the eCommerce department </li>
<li>Improved product data integrity to allow customers to better search for the product they needed </li>
<li>Founded in-house WordPress ecommerce website initiative to save up to $60,000 per website built </li>
<li>Designed and built eCommerce websites for Success Academy, CBRE, and Santander </li>
<li>Redesigned the eCommerce website to improve conversions and SEO </li>
<li>Coordinated website development efforts between stakeholders, third party partners, clients, and salespeople</li>
</ul>
<h2>Education</h2>
<p><strong>DePaul University</strong> · Master in Human-Computer Interaction · <i>2014 - 2016</i></p>
<p><strong>Florida Atlantic University</strong> · Master in Psychology · <i>2010 - 2012</i><i><br></i></p>
<p><strong>Bradley University</strong> · Bachelor in Psychology · <i>2006 - 2010</i><i><br></i></p>
<h2>Skills</h2>
<ul>
<li>A/B testing</li>
<li>Analytics</li>
<li>Axure</li>
<li>Card sort</li>
<li>CSS</li>
<li>Facilitating workshops</li>
<li>HTML</li>
<li>Information architecture</li>
<li>Invision</li>
<li>Mobile design</li>
<li>Photoshop</li>
<li>Presentations</li>
<li>Project management</li>
<li>Rapid prototyping</li>
<li>Sketching</li>
<li>Strategy &amp; vision</li>
<li>User flows</li>
<li>User research</li>
<li>Wireframes &amp; mockups</li>
</ul>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About Me</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Miller</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/about-me/"/>
        <id>https://www.ashleymmiller.com/about-me/</id>

        <updated>2021-05-03T19:19:05-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/1/p1eid14vpn1qbo13ugehm146v20g4.jpg" alt="A smiling adult woman sitting in front of a colorful brick background" />
                     Fun facts: I'm wild about anything spooky, especially history or true&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/1/p1eid14vpn1qbo13ugehm146v20g4.jpg" alt="A smiling adult woman sitting in front of a colorful brick background" />
                <div class="half right">
<h2>Fun facts:</h2>
<ul>
<li>I'm wild about anything spooky, especially history or true crime</li>
<li>I think octopus are neat</li>
<li>I have video proof of me chopping a thrown apple in half with a Civil War cavalry sword</li>
<li>My Dragonball Z fansite was featured in a magazine when I was a kid</li>
</ul>
<p class="clear">I could never decide what I wanted to be when I grew up. I wanted to be an artist, a criminologist, a programmer, a psychologist, a researcher, a teacher. Though I first started making websites when I was 11 years old, I ended up going into Psychology. I got a Bachelors from Bradley University and a Masters from Florida Atlantic University. I got a job as an instructor at Illinois Central College. After deciding to leave academia, a former professor helped me find my way to a career that would combine all of those childhood aspirations (except criminology, but we'll see where my career takes me).</p>
<p>I ended up going to DePaul University for a second Masters in Human-Computer Interaction. Through that program, I've gotten many wonderful opportunities to grow in a career that allows me to impact so many things.</p>
<p>My career has been defined by my inability to pick a lane and stay in it. So I don't.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/uxashleymiller/">Connect with me on LinkedIn.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/captainuxa/" title="Link: https://www.instagram.com/captainuxa/">Or you can look at my Instagram. It's mostly cat pictures.</a></p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Crowd-sourced Wi-Fi reporting</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Miller</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/crowd-sourced-wi-fi-reporting/"/>
        <id>https://www.ashleymmiller.com/crowd-sourced-wi-fi-reporting/</id>

        <updated>2021-05-03T20:53:23-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/p1eicnsrgd1ablhbn1t9g1oah4cv3.png" alt="A screen with a rudimentary map and a button on an android device" />
                     Project In an effort to modernize day-to-day activities in the stores,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/p1eicnsrgd1ablhbn1t9g1oah4cv3.png" alt="A screen with a rudimentary map and a button on an android device" />
                <div class="project-description">
<h2>Project</h2>
<p>In an effort to modernize day-to-day activities in the stores, business gave them handheld and tablet devices. The new devices required nearly constant Wi-Fi connection. We heard constant complaints about the connectivity and speed. Store employees specifically called out being embarrassed to use the devices in front of customers because of how slow they were.</p>
<p>The team responsible for in-store internet had no time or money to invest in new internet hardware. When discussing their issue, we realized we may be able to help them collect data to plead their case. I designed a tool that would allow store employees to report Wi-Fi strength for different parts of the store.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/p1eihkjcvc64lugs1msglnhqqn6.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcvc64lugs1msglnhqqn6-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcvc64lugs1msglnhqqn6-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcvc64lugs1msglnhqqn6-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcvc64lugs1msglnhqqn6-lg.jpg 1024w"  alt="An example of one of the flows" width="1494" height="757">
<figcaption >An example of one of the flows</figcaption>
</figure>
<ul>
<li>My role: Lead UX designer</li>
<li>Team: Product owner, UI designer, researcher</li>
</ul>
<h2>Objective</h2>
<ul>
<li>Create a tool that allows store employees to record Wi-Fi strength at different locations within the store</li>
<li>Collect and send that information to the internet team so they have data to argue for a budget to improve Wi-Fi in stores</li>
</ul>
<h2>Work</h2>
<p>We found several limitations from the beginning:</p>
<ul>
<li>Every store had a different floor plans</li>
<li>There were no maps of each store</li>
</ul>
<p>Both of those limitations meant that we were unable to provide maps as part of the tool. So instead of personalizing the tool per store, I created a checklist of departments that a store employee could go through. They could skip a department if they didn't have it, ex. the training room. </p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/p1eihkjcv9p6m1qrp704126du0f4.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcv9p6m1qrp704126du0f4-xs.png 300w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcv9p6m1qrp704126du0f4-sm.png 480w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcv9p6m1qrp704126du0f4-md.png 768w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcv9p6m1qrp704126du0f4-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Finalized design for the tablets" width="774" height="998">
<figcaption >Finalized design for the tablets</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>But because departments could be in wildly different locations depending on the building, I wanted to try and measure some kind of geographical-based signals. Without a floor plan, though, I decided that maybe we could draw some kind of rudimentary map to represent the store and doors. I had no idea how that was going to go during research. The map looked like a square faced with buck teeth.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/p1eihkjcvbgfldi416nn2katq35.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcvbgfldi416nn2katq35-xs.png 300w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcvbgfldi416nn2katq35-sm.png 480w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcvbgfldi416nn2katq35-md.png 768w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/4/responsive/p1eihkjcvbgfldi416nn2katq35-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Prototype concept of the corner mapping design" width="774" height="998">
<figcaption >Prototype concept of the corner mapping design</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>We brought paper printouts to stores to research. The managers were thrilled. This would give them an opportunity to provide feedback to improve their stores. Even though we were asking them to add yet another task to their overloaded days, they described how they would add the Wi-Fi tracker to their daily walks. They understood the rudimentary map. The only request was to provide a handheld version, because they preferred the handheld device to the tablet.</p>
<h2>End result</h2>
<p>Unfortunately, business rejected the app proposal. They were concerned about the labor hours we were asking managers to perform for us.</p>
<h2>Reflection</h2>
<p>This project was something we were very passionate about, something the managers were passionate about, and something that the internet team was passionate about. We failed to pass on that excitement to business.</p>
<p>Going forward, we carefully teed up every product we would present to business. We made sure to tighten our presentation style, address the needs of every individual executive, and make sure we had an iron-clad reasoning for each and every decision. It wouldn't necessarily guarantee us success at all times in the future, but we had a much better average.</p>
<p>The project wasn't a complete loss, though. Parts of it were later cannibalized when business asked for an update to the troubleshooting tool to measure Wi-Fi connectivity when stores reported an issue.</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Streamlined purchase of restricted products</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Miller</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/streamlined-purchase-of-restricted-products/"/>
        <id>https://www.ashleymmiller.com/streamlined-purchase-of-restricted-products/</id>

        <updated>2021-05-03T20:53:12-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/p1eico2du4viv1iqmse63mn79e3.png" alt="" />
                     Project There are certain types of products that are used to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/p1eico2du4viv1iqmse63mn79e3.png" alt="" />
                <div class="project-description">
<h2>Project</h2>
<p>There are certain types of products that are used to transport water, but are not safe for human consumption, usually because of whatever the product was made out of. These items are restricted. When selling one of these items, a retailer has to make it clear that the item cannot legally be used for human consumption (otherwise known as potable water). </p>
<p>On Zoro.com, if a customer attempted to purchase one of these items, they would have to fill out a form before the product could be added to the cart. After purchasing, the order would be flagged. A customer service agent (CSA) would then have to manually interact with the order multiple times along its lifecycle. Most of the orders got canceled because of some unforeseen failure, ex. the form address didn't match the shipping address. While the amount of orders were small (~10,000/year), it still amounted to potentially hours of manual labor and frustrated customers.</p>
<ul>
<li>My role: Lead UX designer</li>
<li>Team: Legal team, customer service team</li>
</ul>
<h2>Objective</h2>
<ul>
<li>Reduce customer frustration with canceled orders</li>
<li>Minimize the amount of manual processes applied to the order</li>
</ul>
<h2>Work</h2>
<p>I first heard of this problem while sitting with one of the CSAs during a ride along. She explained that this customer was furious because they had ordered this spigot two weeks ago and he still hadn't gotten a notification. After looking at the website, I understood how the customer might have been led to make a mistake.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/p1eih8ts1h178s1nvi15dm1u6v8p83.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1h178s1nvi15dm1u6v8p83-xs.png 300w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1h178s1nvi15dm1u6v8p83-sm.png 480w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1h178s1nvi15dm1u6v8p83-md.png 768w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1h178s1nvi15dm1u6v8p83-lg.png 1024w"  alt="The original flow to purchase a restricted product" width="1105" height="903">
<figcaption >The original flow to purchase a restricted product</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I mapped out the current flow from the customer side and from the CSA side, to determine the major pain points. The customer jumped through several hoops on the product page, including digitally signing a poorly worded agreement. The CSA then had to manually check every single order and may even call the customer.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/p1eih8ts1j1m33of45rar9klfm4.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1j1m33of45rar9klfm4-xs.png 300w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1j1m33of45rar9klfm4-sm.png 480w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1j1m33of45rar9klfm4-md.png 768w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1j1m33of45rar9klfm4-lg.png 1024w"  alt="The updated flow" width="803" height="624">
<figcaption >The updated flow</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>After researching competitors and the parent company, I came up with a draft flow and design. I reviewed it with the legal team to make sure that the company was still protected against lawsuits. They approved the flow.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/p1eih8ts1l6s5132t6r137g17am5.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1l6s5132t6r137g17am5-xs.png 300w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1l6s5132t6r137g17am5-sm.png 480w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1l6s5132t6r137g17am5-md.png 768w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/5/responsive/p1eih8ts1l6s5132t6r137g17am5-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Recommended updates to the cart page" width="924" height="726">
<figcaption >Recommended updates to the cart page</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>End result</h2>
<ul>
<li>Clarified the purchase for the customer</li>
<li>Eliminated manual processes</li>
<li>Maintained legal protection for the company</li>
</ul>
<h2>Reflection</h2>
<p>Unfortunately, this project never got prioritized for development. There were many projects vying for resources and, because these restricted products made up such a low number of overall purchases, there just wasn't a demand to fix the process.</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Organizing 150 links into categories</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Miller</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/organizing-150-links-into-categories/"/>
        <id>https://www.ashleymmiller.com/organizing-150-links-into-categories/</id>

        <updated>2021-05-03T20:53:02-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/6/p1eihsve4g15do172116kvgidaba5.jpg" alt="A panoramic shot of the room once we were done organizing and planning out the release calendar, at the very end of the project" />
                     Project As part of the modernization effort, business wanted to include&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/6/p1eihsve4g15do172116kvgidaba5.jpg" alt="A panoramic shot of the room once we were done organizing and planning out the release calendar, at the very end of the project" />
                <div class="project-description">
<div>
<h2>Project</h2>
<p>As part of the modernization effort, business wanted to include the most important links from the very expansive intranet. Ultimately they asked us to include ~150 links in our new app meant to help the managers run their stores.</p>
<ul>
<li>My role: UX designer</li>
<li>Team: UX designer, researcher</li>
</ul>
<h2>Objective</h2>
<ul>
<li>Organize 150 links in a way that would be easy for managers to find what they need</li>
</ul>
<h2>Work</h2>
<p>150 links are overwhelming for a single person to organize and I was unfamiliar with almost all of the links. Another UX designer, a researcher, and I decided to lock ourselves in an empty storage closet for a week. We divided and conquered. Each of us took about 50 links, visited them, and contributed information to the shared spreadsheet. This collaboration was done in a day. We spent the next couple days organizing and reorganizing these links onto the walls of the storage closet. We ended up with about 7 top level categories. </p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/6/p1eii59tjc1r8517j6o5edplirq3.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/6/responsive/p1eii59tjc1r8517j6o5edplirq3-xs.png 300w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/6/responsive/p1eii59tjc1r8517j6o5edplirq3-sm.png 480w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/6/responsive/p1eii59tjc1r8517j6o5edplirq3-md.png 768w ,https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/6/responsive/p1eii59tjc1r8517j6o5edplirq3-lg.png 1024w"  alt="A sample of the spreadsheet we used to keep track of our links and organize our thoughts" width="2000" height="796">
<figcaption >A sample of the spreadsheet we used to keep track of our links and organize our thoughts</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Our guesses were good, but we wanted to make sure they resonated with the stores.</p>
<p>Our researcher sent out a series of card sorts. Each test sorted around 30 links. Some of the tests had category names already assigned, while some were completely open.</p>
<h2>End Result</h2>
<ul>
<li>46% of links remained where we categorized them</li>
<li>18% of links were categorized inconclusively, so we made our best guess based on the comments from employees</li>
<li>36% of links were originally categorized wrong, so we moved them based on employee recommendations</li>
</ul>
<p>For a bunch of people completely unfamiliar with the links, the store employees agreed with us more than I expected. </p>
<p>Once the categories were finalized, we presented the results to our business partners. After using data to answer any questions and assuage any fears, business agreed with our proposal. </p>
<p>To assist our dev team, we then used the sticky notes room to organize every link into a release calendar.</p>
<h2>Reflection </h2>
<p>Ultimately, this app was discontinued once the intranet website was updated to be responsive, but it's hard not to feel satisfied with the amount of work that got done. The photos themselves speak of to the absurdity of this project, but by dividing responsibilities and really focusing, we got the work done in a timely manner.</p>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Founding an eCommerce Wordpress initiative</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Miller</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/founding-an-ecommerce-wordpress-initiative/"/>
        <id>https://www.ashleymmiller.com/founding-an-ecommerce-wordpress-initiative/</id>

        <updated>2021-05-03T20:52:49-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/7/p1eii6glp017qd549j5k1n5sf273.png" alt="" />
                     Project The salespeople within the company often needed to create microsites&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/7/p1eii6glp017qd549j5k1n5sf273.png" alt="" />
                <div class="project-description">
<h2>Project</h2>
<p>The salespeople within the company often needed to create microsites for their clients to sell branded products. The existing inventory management software was so niche that a single developer existed for it. That single developer was expensive, severely backlogged, and created mid-90s-esque websites.</p>
<p>After redesigning the blog for the Blue Soda Promo website and seeing the work by another designer, I believed I had a solution.</p>
<ul>
<li>My role: Lead designer, website manager</li>
<li>Team: Developer</li>
</ul>
<h2>Objective</h2>
<ul>
<li>Find a way to streamline the creation of eCommerce microsites</li>
</ul>
<h2>Work</h2>
<p>I created a quick proposal for my boss: Let me use Wordpress, which we've already used successfully for the blog and our designer was using to make another microsite for a niche product, to create a series of eCommerce sites. I had even found a plugin developer that would be able to integrate with the ancient inventory management software, given the right attributes.</p>
<p>My boss approved the idea and I got to work.</p>
<h2>End result</h2>
<p>My eCommerce initiative was a wild success. I could knock them out in a week or two, work directly with the salespeople and clients, and my websites saved the company approximately $60,000 per site I created. They were infinitely more valuable because I could then also train the salespeople to update the products as necessary.</p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-columns="3">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/7/gallery/p1eii6hc8i121vkl94i11riihgi7.png" data-size="2000x2336"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/7/gallery/p1eii6hc8i121vkl94i11riihgi7-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="768" height="897"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/7/gallery/p1eii6mnvo1vonvmlj4mlj4a8t4-2.jpg" data-size="2000x4158"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/7/gallery/p1eii6mnvo1vonvmlj4mlj4a8t4-2-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1597"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/7/gallery/p1eii6mnvk1tdepmetqg164mj6h3.jpg" data-size="2000x4852"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ashleymmiller.com/media/posts/7/gallery/p1eii6mnvk1tdepmetqg164mj6h3-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1863"></a></figure>
</div></div>
<h2>Reflection</h2>
<p>This was relatively early on in my career, before I completed my Human-Computer Interaction degree. It was wildly out of the scope of the data entry job I'd been hired for, but I saw an opportunity to fix a big issue some of my coworkers had. I think it was here that I started building the confidence I would need in later jobs. Since then, I've grown even more incapable of staying in my own lane.</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
